Nikolai Dorofeev

Frontend Developer

IT specialist with experience in **Vue ecosystem**. Created frontend Single Page Applications with **Server Side Rendering** and **Static Site Generation**. Implemented **motion design** fragments.

⊕ d0rich.me ☑ n.dorofeev.pro@gmail.com ♠ d0rich ← linkedin.com/in/d0rich ← t.me/d0rich ← Tbilisi, Georgia

Work Experience

Senior Backend Developer Exactpro

Aug 2023 - Present (1 year 2 months)

- Designed and implemented an intuitive data processing Python framework, winning team's development time on proprietary file format operations and unifying crucial parts of the codebase;
- Identified and resolved performance bottlenecks, enhancing the system's responsiveness and efficiency by 400% for pandas operations and up to 100% for vanilla Python operations:
- Employed SQLite for high-performance data storage and retrieval tasks, saving 6 hours
 of senior analysts' time per week and ensuring low amount of RAM usage;
- Developed sophisticated tools for reconciling data across different trading protocols, providing a highly-efficient way to reveal errors in the system.

Fullstack Developer Red-Green Life Design

Nov 2023 - Aug 2024 (10 months)

- Developed the mobile client using React Native and Expo, delivering a smooth and responsive user experience;
- Worked closely with the designer to ensure that the UI/UX aligned with user expectations and adhered to design specifications;
- Built and maintained RESTful APIs using NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL, and Prisma ORM, providing reliable support for the mobile application;
- Configured OAuth2.0 authentication, providing greater User Experience with one-tap authentification;
- Automated several environments deployments via CI/CD pipelines using GitHub Actions, saving time and effort for the team.

Senior Fullstack Developer Exactpro

Jul 2021 - Aug 2023 (2 years 2 months)

- Designed and developed a custom documentation portal with VueJS, VueX, NodeJS, GraphQL, increasing accessibility of the crucial data and speeding up the process of its publishing for the employees without deep technology understanding;
- Led the development of a highly deployable and easily maintainable documentation framework based on NuxtJS, NodeJS, and Tailwind CSS, speeding up time-to-market and reducing maintenance costs for the proprietary documentation portals;
- Automated synchronization of the documentation portal with the GitHub repositories and Algolia search engine, ensuring the documentation is always up-to-date and easily searchable;
- Developed reusable high-performant microservices in Python and Kotlin, focusing on gRPC and RabbitMQ communication within a Docker / Kubernetes environment, saving development time for the several teams;
- Automated the seamless deployment of static websites and npm packages via CI/CD pipelines using GitHub Actions, GitLab CI, and Jenkins, saving the team time and effort;
- Architected the winning solution for the Swift Hackathon 2022, enabling traceability of digital assets across blockchains. It helped to bring new clients to the company.

Languages

• English: Upper-Intermediate

• French: Intermediate

Russian: Native

Skills



CSS frameworks

DApps

Projects

- <u>d0xigen</u>: 📴 Docs to breath life into your project
- <u>d0rich design system</u>: 🎨 Design system inspired by Persona 5 UI
- <u>DNetwork</u>: First true blockchain social network (built on TON)
- <u>BigFiles</u>: Ton Drive is an intuitive and responsive interface designed for Telegram Web
 Apps. It allows seamless uploading, viewing, and managing of large files, bypassing
 Telegram's 2GB file limit. Users experience smooth interactions while the backend
 handles robust file processing and storage.
- ton-validators-map: Building a map of TON validators

Certificates

- Enterprise Patterns (<u>foxminded.ua</u>, May 2023): Course Page, Certificate, Verify Certificate
- Architecting With Google Kubernetes Engine (Coursera, Oct 2021): Certificate
- Fundamentals Of Digital Marketing (<u>Google Digital Garage</u>, Jul 2021): Certificate

Education

Bachelor of Science - BS, Information Systems and Technologies in Business Tomsk Polytechnic University

Sep 2018 - Jul 2022 (3 years 11 months)

This program is aimed at training specialists in the field of information systems and technologies in business, who are able to solve problems of business management and economic activity using modern information technologies and systems. Projects were related to the development of ecommerce systems and integration with ERP systems.

Main learning stack: ASP.NET + MS SQL.

However, students was free to choose any technology stack for their projects.

Used technologies: Node.js, Python Flask, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Firebase, Docker, etc.

Diploma project: distributed full-stack framework for trading automation implemented with Node.js and Vue.js.